让我们总结一下我们在本次讲座中学到的一些概念。这就是全部
Let’s summarise some of the concepts that we’ve learned in this lecture. It’s all
关于三维空间中的运动。首先，我们介绍了这个概念
being about motion in three-dimensional space. First of all, we introduced the concept of
平移速度，即一个点的X，Y和Z分量的变化率
translational velocity that is the rate of change of the X, Y and Z components of a point
在空间中，我们定义相对于参考坐标系。
in space and we define that with respect to a reference coordinate frame.
我们介绍了角速度的概念，即矢量。方向
We introduced the concept of angular velocity and that is a vector quantity. The direction
矢量的矢量是身体在该时刻绕其旋转的轴
of the vector is the axis about which the body is rotating at that instance in time
并且矢量的大小是旋转速度。角速度有三个组成部分：
and the magnitude of the vector is the rate of rotation. Angular velocity has three components:
相对于参考坐标系定义的ωx，ωy和ωz。
ωx, ωy, and ωz defined with respect to a reference coordinate frame.
平移速度V和角速度ω组合成我们参考的量
Translational velocity V and angular velocity ω are combined into a quantity we referred
作为空间速度或有时称为扭曲。这是一个六元素的矢量。
to as spatial velocity or sometimes referred to as twist. It’s a six-element vector.
我们引入了一个偏斜对称矩阵。这是一个矩阵，其转置等于
We introduced a skew symmetric matrix. This is a matrix whose transpose is equal to the
消极的。当我们谈论三维旋转时，相关
negative of itself. When we are talking about rotation in three dimensions, the relevant
偏斜对称矩阵是3.3元素矩阵，它是矢量的函数。有
skew symmetric matrix is a 3.3 element matrix which is a function of a vector. There is
这个身体的角速度和时间之间非常重要的关系
a really important relationship between the angular velocity of that body and the time
旋转矩阵的导数。
derivative of the rotation matrix.
对于一个有六个关节的机器人，我们可以写出这样的关系，它与之相关
For a robot with six joints, we can write a relationship like this, which relates the
机器人关节角度与机器人末端执行器空间速度的变化率，
rate of change of the robot joint angles to this spatial velocity of the robots end effector,
这种关系是用六乘六雅可比矩阵表示的
and the relationship is in terms of a six by six Jacobian matrix which we denote by
符号J.雅可比矩阵是关节角度本身的函数。
the symbol J. The Jacobian matrix is a function of the joint angles themselves.
我们可以写出机器人关节角速度Qdot和空间之间的这种一般关系
We can write this general relationship between the robot joint angle velocity Qdot and spatial
雅各比矩阵的速度。如果雅可比矩阵是正方形，那么我们
velocity in terms of the Jacobian matrix. If the Jacobian matrix is square, then we
可以反转这种关系，并允许我们转换所需的空间速度
can invert the relationship and that allows us to transform a desired spatial velocity
对于机器人的末端执行器进入机器人电机的关节角速率需要达到。
for the robot’s end effector into the joint angle rates of the robots’ motors need to attain.
任何机器人关节的运动都会影响机器人末端执行器的空间速度。
The motion of any robot joint affects the spatial velocity of the robot’s end effector.
我们可以想到雅各比矩阵的列在那种关系中描述。
We can think of the columns of the Jacobian matrix as described at that relationship.
第一列告诉我们第一个关节如何影响空间速度。该
The first column tells us how the spatial velocity is affected by the first joint. The
第二列告诉我们空间速度如何受到第二个关节的影响，依此类推。
second column tells us how the spatial velocity is affected by the second joint and so on.
我们可以将它视为每个关节的效果的总和，我们添加它们
We can think of it as a summation of the effect of each of the individual joints, we add them
一起确定机器人末端执行器的整体空间速度。
all together to determine the overall spatial velocity of the robot’s end effector.
在某些情况下，机器人雅可比行列式可以是单一的，并且当不止一个联合原因时
In some cases, the robot Jacobian can be singular and that’s when more than one joint cause
与机器人末端执行器完全相同的运动，雅可比行列中有两列
exactly the same motion of the robot end effector, that there are two columns in the Jacobian
矩阵是相同的，使机器人奇异。
matrix which are identical and that makes the robot singular.
对于在三维空间中移动的机器人，雅可比矩阵总是有六个
For robots that move in three-dimensional space, the Jacobian matrix always has six
角色但列数等于机器人具有的关节数。如果
roles but the number of columns is equal to the number of joints that the robot has. If
机器人有六个关节，雅可比矩阵将是方形的，我们可以将它反转这么长时间
the robot got six joints, the Jacobian matrix will be square and we can invert it so long
因为机器人不是单一的配置。对于接头少于六个的机器人
as the robot is not in a singular configuration. For a robot with less than six joints which
我们称之为欠驱动机器人，雅可比不是方形的。为了平方
we refer to as an under-actuated robot, the Jacobian is not square. In order to square
我们可以将它用于控制目的，我们需要消除雅可比行列中的一些行
it up so we can use it for control purposes, we need to eliminate some rows in that Jacobian
矩阵。对于具有六个以上关节的机器人的情况，我们称之为过度驱动
matrix. For the case of a robot with more than six joints, which we refer to as an over-actuated
机器人，雅可比行列有很多列而不是行。如果我们想要反转它
robot, the Jacobian has many more columns than has rows. If we want to invert it for
为了控制目的，我们需要使用一种称为伪逆的技术。我们也可以思考
control purposes, we need to use a technique called the Pseudo Inverse. We can also think
关于像这样的机器人有大量的备用关节，我们可以使用它
about the robot like this as having a large number of spare joints and we can use this
以独立于姿势的方式控制机器人手臂形状的配置
to control the configuration with the shape of the robot arm independently of the pose
其末端执行器。我们称之为零空间运动。
of its end effector. We refer to this as null space motion.
我们可以将相对于一帧表示的速度转换为相对于另一帧的速度
We can transform velocity expressed with respect to one frame to velocity with respect to another
由雅可比矩阵构成的帧，并且雅可比矩阵是相对姿势的函数
frame by a Jacobian matrix, and that Jacobian matrix is a function of the relative pose
两帧之间。特别是，它是两者之间相对方向的函数
between the two frames. In particular, it’s a function of the relative orientation between
两个坐标框架。
the two coordinate frames.
我们可以使用该速度变换技术来确定机器人的末端效应器
We can use that velocity transform technique in order to determine the robot’s end-effector
空间速度相对于末端效应器坐标系而不是世界坐标
spatial velocity with respect to the end-effector coordinate frame rather than the world coordinate
框架，这通常是一个非常有用和方便的东西。因此我们可以定义
frame, and that’s typically a very useful and convenient thing to have. We can therefore define
雅可比矩阵的一个变体，它给出了第六帧中的速度，即末端效应器坐标系。
a variant of the Jacobian matrix which gives us the velocity in frame six, the end-effector coordinate frame.
角速度是一个有点抽象的概念，有点难以想象。
Angular velocity is a somewhat abstract concept that’s a little difficult to visualize.
我们经常谈论车身在侧倾，俯仰和偏航角方面的方向
We often talk about the orientation of a body in terms of its roll, pitch, and yaw angles
因此，根据速率表达物体的旋转速度更直观
so it’s more intuitive to express the rotational velocity of an object in terms of the rates
其滚动，俯仰和偏航角度的变化。我们可以导出一个3x3雅可比矩阵
of change of its roll, pitch, and yaw angles. We can derive a 3x3 Jacobian matrix which
将滚转，俯仰和偏航角速率转换为传统的角速度。然后我们
transforms roll, pitch, and yaw angle rates into traditional angular velocity. Then we
可以引入空间速度矢量的变体，我们替换角速度
can introduce a variant of a spatial velocity vector and we replace the angular velocity
具有滚动，俯仰，偏航速度分量的部件。这会导致一些叫做的事情
component with a roll, pitch, yaw velocity component. This leads to something called
分析雅可比矩阵并将机器人关节角速率映射到修改后的空间
the Analytic Jacobian matrix and this maps robot joint angle rates to the modified spatial
速度矢量。
velocity vector.
我们在三个维度上介绍了速度椭球的概念。椭圆体
We introduced the concept of the velocity ellipsoid in three dimensions. The ellipsoid
谈到机器人在不同方向上实现速度的能力
says something about the ability of the robot to achieve velocity in different directions
在三维空间。末端执行器能够在这个方向上移动得最快
in three-dimensional space. The end-effector is able to move most quickly in the direction
平行于椭圆体的最长轴并且它平行于方向移动得最慢
parallel to the longest axis of the ellipsoid and it moves most slowly parallel to the direction
椭圆体的最短轴。我们可以描述椭圆体的整体形状
of the shortest axis of the ellipsoid. We can describe the overall shape of the ellipsoid
就我们称之为可操纵性的标量度量而言，它说的是一些东西
in terms of a scalar measure which we call manipulability, and it says something about
椭圆体的紧凑性。如果可操纵性等于1，则椭圆体实际上是
the compactness of the ellipsoid. If the manipulability is equal to one, the ellipsoid is in fact
球体，我们将其称为各向同性运动情况。机器人能够平等移动
the sphere, and we refer to this as the isotropic motion case. The robot is able to move equally
快速向任何方向发展。在可操纵性等于零的情况下，这表示运动
quickly in any direction. In the case of manipulability is equal to zero, that indicates that motion
在一个分区方向上是不可能的并且三维椭圆体已经存在
in one partition direction is not possible and the three-dimensional ellipsoid has been
扁平成椭圆形板。
flattened into an elliptical plate.